JOSEPH JOHNSON

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+44 7512 610315

joseph.johnson27001@gmail .com

Potton, Bedfordshire, UK

joseph-johnson27001.github .io/Website/

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- Chart.js
- VueJS
- Vuex
- Vuetify
- Bootstrap
- JSON
- PostgreSQL
- SCSS
- Typescript
- ¡Query
- Node & Yarn Package Manager
- GitHub
- Wordpress
- Elementor Page Builder

EDUCATION

Front End Tech Degree

Team Treehouse

Remote | 2020

Ancient History

Royal Holloway: University of London Surrey, UK | 2013

PROFILE

An ambitious web developer, with a passion for creating clean, responsive and user-friendly websites. Along with my professional experience, I have developed a cryptocurrency tracking application, a quiz application and several other demo sites, all of which are viewable on my portfolio page. I now hope to join an exciting team where I can contribute to projects for clients, whilst continuing to broaden my programming knowledge.

EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

QUALIFICATION CHECK | LONDON & REMOTE | AUG 2022 - PRESENT

- Using Vue.js, Chart.js, Google Sheets and multiple API's, developed and created
 the Qualification Check 'Country Insights' tool. This product would show users
 up-to-date verification turnaround times, fraudulent rates, education
 information, student mobility information and country level information. It was
 developed in such a way that the research team could immediately update any
 relevant information on the user-facing site
- Working with backend developers, produced the client analytics tool. This showed users, in multiple graph forms, their verifications data from over the last 24 months. Users were able to select different date and selection parameters for each section and then download their own personal reports
- Created warning and notification options to alert users of any events which might impact verification times. These could be simply updated by the relevant team member to appear on the user facing site
- Using Vue.js and element-plus, continually updated the company site. This
 included periodic user improvements, fixing bugs and developing new features
 for the sites UI and UX
- Monitored any errors using the Sentry error handling tool
- Maintained the company Wordpress site This included normal day-to-day changes, blog posts layout improvements along with plugin and analytics updates
- Presented, both online and in-person, completed projects to members of the executive management team
- Liaised with members of the broader Qualification Check team to develop ideas and designs for all projects
- After discussing ideas with team members, generated possible solutions to help improve both the staff and user experience on their sites
- Assisted in creating more automated processes to help increase productivity
- Engaged in code reviews and monthly sprint planning with other members of the development team

JOSEPH JOHNSON

WFB DFVFI OPFR

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

ONLINE ENGLISH TEACHER

iTutorgroup | Remote | Aug 2018 - Apr 2020

OPERATIONS ADMINISTRATOR

Cambridge Assessment | Cambridge | Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

ENGLISH TEACHER

Schools Affiliated with the Beijing University of Technology | Beijing | Feb 2016 - Jul 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

- ISO 27001 Lead Implementer
- ISO 27005 Risk Management
- 120 Hour TEFL Certification

LANGUAGES

- English | Fluent
- Mandarin | Basic
- French | Basic

INTERESTS

- Travel
- Music
- Football
- Photography
- Cooking
- Weightlifting
- Chess
- History
- Psychology
- Guitar
- Studying Mandarin

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

JUNIOR DEVELOPER

DIRECT BUSINESS SOLUTIONS | REMOTE | APR 2021 - JAN 2022

- Utilised 'Vue.JS' and 'Vuetify' to develop a scheduling application, with built-in reminders, timers, and notifications. This product was then used by the entire sales team to assist with the business' daily sales operation
- Linked the above scheduling application to 'Microsoft Outlook' and 'Microsoft Todo' through the use of an API
- Implemented a service worker in order for the sales team to use the above application offline
- Discussed with other members of the team how best to utilise UX and UI features for the staff website and updated the site accordingly
- Created editable data tables, with information drawn from back end databases, utilising both PostgreSQL and VueJS
- Completed various ad hoc coding tasks, including database management fixes, editing web page styling, and re-working programming functions
- Utilised the 'liveshare' feature on 'Visual Studio Code' in order to code with other team members

FREELANCE WORK

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Using JavaScript, developed a minimum viable product for an information security policy website
- Created a photography website using 'Wordpress,' the Divi theme and the Elementor page builder
- Liaised with customers about design aspects and provided suggestions based on their requirements

PERSONAL WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

REMOTE | JUN 2020 - PRESENT

- Built a cryptocurrency tracking webpage using multiple API's, ReactJS and Chart.js
- Created an online quiz application, using JavaScript programming, with multiple questions and categories for the viewer to choose from
- Developed a Star Wars Themed portfolio for Darth Vader, based on online designs
- Utilised 'Bootstrap' to create a landing page for an imitation tour company
- Developed a landing page for a "cliche" business company
- Developed an online personal portfolio page company using HTML, CSS and Vanilla JavaScript
- Achieved the highest available marks in the Team Treehouse 'Front End Web Development Techdegree'